<content type="application/x.deki0805+xml" title="showPopup"><body xmlns:eval="http://mindtouch.com/2007/dekiscript">
<div class="noinclude"><span class="script">template.XULRefMeth()</span></div>
<dl> <dt><span class="script">template.XULMeth2("showPopup", "( element, x, y, popupType, anchor, align )")</span> <span style="border: 1px solid rgb(152, 152, 240); background-color: rgb(221, 221, 255); font-size: 9px; vertical-align: text-top;">Deprecated in Mozilla 1.9</span></dt> <dd>Return type: <em>no return value</em><br /> <em>Deprecated in favor of openPopup and <span>openPopupAtScreen</span></em></dd> <dd>Opens a popup element. There are two ways of specifying where the popup appears, either at a specific screen position, or relative to some element in the window. If either <var>x</var> or <var>y</var> are set to values, the popup will appear at the screen coordinate (<var>x</var>,<var>y</var>). If <var>x</var> and <var>y</var> are <code>-1</code>, the popup will be positioned relative to the <var>element</var> specified as the first argument. This is what you might do to show a popup below a button, for example. In this latter case, the <var>anchor</var> and <var>align</var> arguments may be used to further control where the popup appears relative to the element. The <var>anchor</var> argument corresponds to the <span class="script">template.XULAttr("popupanchor")</span> attribute on the element. The <var>align</var> argument corresponds to the <span class="script">template.XULAttr("popupalign")</span> attribute on the element. The <var>anchor</var> and <var>align</var> arguments are ignored if either <var>x</var> or <var>y</var> are not <code>-1</code>.</dd>
</dl>
<dl> <dd>To have a popup appear relative to another element yet still offset by some number of pixels, determine the actual screen position of the element using the <span class="script">template.XULProp("boxObject")</span>.screenX and <span class="script">template.XULProp("boxObject")</span>.screenY properties of the element, and use those as the <var>x</var> and <var>y</var> arguments offset by the desired values.</dd>
</dl>
<dl> <dd>The <var>popupType</var> should be either the string <code>popup</code>, <code>context</code>, or <code>tooltip</code>. Each type of popup is intended to be displayed only temporarily; they are not expected to be displayed permanently. Only one popup may be displayed at a time.</dd>
</dl>
<div class="noinclude">
<p><span class="script"> wiki.languages( { "fr": "fr/XUL/M\u00e9thodes/showPopup", "ja": "ja/XUL/Method/showPopup", "pl": "pl/XUL/Metoda/showPopup" } ) </span></p>
</div></body></content>