<content type="application/x.deki0805+xml" title="allowevents"><body xmlns:eval="http://mindtouch.com/2007/dekiscript">
<div class="noinclude"><span class="script">XULRefAttr()</span></div>
<dl> <dt><span class="script">XULAttr("allowevents")</span></dt> <dd>Type: <em>boolean</em></dd> <dd>If true, events are passed to children of the element. Otherwise, events are passed to the element only.</dd>
</dl>
<div class="noinclude">
<p>On <span class="script">XULElem("listitem")</span> and <span class="script">XULElem("titlebar")</span> elements, mouse events normally do not get sent to their children; instead they are retargeted to the <span class="script">XULElem("listitem")</span> and <span class="script">XULElem("titlebar")</span> element itself. This means that elements placed inside a listitem do not respond to events, and instead clicking the mouse simply selects that item within the list. By setting the allowevents attribute to <code>true</code>, this special behavior is disabled, and the events are targeted the same as other elements.</p>
<p>For <span class="script">XULElem("menu")</span>, <span class="script">XULElem("menuseparator")</span>, <span class="script">XULElem("menuitem")</span> and <span class="script">XULElem("treecol")</span> elements, as well as menu buttons, and the popup <span class="script">XULElem("datepicker")</span>, mouse events are also retargeted to the element itself. However, the allowevents attribute is handled in a different way. Instead, the allowevents may be set to <code>true</code> on a descendant instead. This does the same thing in that it allows events to be targeted normally, but allows this to be different for each descendant.</p>
<p>This behavior is used for menus, for instance, to allow a menu button to behave as a menu when clicking on it, yet have part of the menu behave as a button. For the latter, the allowevents attribute is set to <code>true</code> to have a click on the child button receive events instead of targeting all events at the menu.</p>
<p><span class="script"> wiki.languages( { "de": "de/XUL/Attribute/allowevents", "fr": "fr/XUL/Attributs/allowevents", "ja": "ja/XUL/Attribute/allowevents", "pl": "pl/XUL/Atrybut/allowevents" } ) </span></p>
</div>
</body></content>