<content type="application/x.deki0805+xml" title="popup.position"><body xmlns:eval="http://mindtouch.com/2007/dekiscript">
<div class="noinclude"><span class="script">template.XULRefAttr()</span></div>
<dl> <dt><span class="script">template.XULAttr("popup.position", "position")</span></dt> <dd>Type: <em>one of the values below</em></dd> <dd>The <code>position</code> attribute determines where the popup appears relative to the element the user clicked to invoke the popup. This allows you to place the popup on one side of a button.  Note that a context menu will never respect this attribute, always appearing relative to the mouse cursor.</dd>
</dl>
<ul> <li><code>after_start</code>: The popup appears underneath the element with the popup's upper-left corner aligned with the lower-left corner of the element. The left edges of the element and the popup are aligned. This is typically used for drop-down menus.</li> <li><code>after_end</code>: The popup appears underneath the element with the popup's upper-right corner aligned with the lower-right corner of the element. The right edges of the element and the popup are aligned.</li> <li><code>before_start</code>: The popup appears above the element with the popup's lower-left corner aligned with the upper-left corner of the element. The left edges of the element and the popup are aligned.</li> <li><code>before_end</code>: The popup appears above the element with the popup's lower-right corner aligned with the upper-right corner of the element. The right edges of the element and the popup are aligned.</li> <li><code>end_after</code>: The popup appears to the right of the element with the popup's lower-left corner aligned with the lower-right corner of the element. The bottom edges of the element and the popup are aligned.</li> <li><code>end_before</code>: The popup appears to the right of the element with the popup's upper-left corner aligned with the upper-right corner of the element. The top edges of the element and the popup are aligned.</li> <li><code>start_after</code>: The popup appears to the left of the element with the popup's lower-right corner aligned with the lower-left corner of the element. The bottom edges of the element and the popup are aligned.</li> <li><code>start_before</code>: The popup appears to the left of the element with the popup's upper-right corner aligned with the upper-left corner of the element. The top edges of the element and the popup are aligned.</li> <li><code>overlap</code>: The popup appears over top of the element with the upper-left corners aligned.</li> <li><code>at_pointer</code>: The popup appears at the same position as the mouse pointer.</li> <li><code>after_pointer</code>: The popup appears at the same horizontal position as the mouse pointer, but vertically, it is placed just below the element.</li>
</ul>
<div class="noinclude">
<h3 name="See_also">See also</h3>
<ul> <li><a title="en/XUL/Attribute/position" href="/en/XUL/Attribute/position">position</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="noinclude">
<p><span class="script"> wiki.languages( { "fr": "fr/XUL/Attributs/popup.position", "ja": "ja/XUL/Attribute/popup.position" } ) </span></p>
</div></body></content>