<content type="application/x.deki0805+xml" title="textbox.type"><body xmlns:eval="http://mindtouch.com/2007/dekiscript">
<div class="noinclude"><span class="script">template.XULRefAttr()</span></div>
<dl> <dt><span class="script">template.XULAttr("textbox.type", "type")</span></dt> <dd>Type: <em>one of the values below</em></dd> <dd>You can set the type attribute to one of the values below for a more specialized type of textbox. Don't set the type if you wish to use a regular textbox.</dd>
</dl>
<ul> <li><code>autocomplete</code>: A textbox that supports autocomplete. For more information about autocomplete textboxes, see the autocomplete documentation (<a title="En/XUL/Textbox (XPFE autocomplete)" href="/En/XUL/Textbox_(XPFE_autocomplete)">XPFE</a> [Thunderbird/SeaMonkey]) (<a title="en/XUL/textbox_(Firefox_autocomplete)" href="/En/XUL/Textbox_(Toolkit_autocomplete)">Firefox</a>)</li> <li><code>number</code>: <span class="script">gecko_minversion_inline("1.9")</span> A textbox that only allows the user to enter numbers. In addition, arrow buttons appear next to the textbox to let the user step through values. There are several attributes that allow the number textbox to be configured, including <span class="script">template.XULAttr("decimalplaces")</span>, <span class="script">template.XULAttr("min")</span>, <span class="script">template.XULAttr("max")</span>, <span class="script">template.XULAttr("increment")</span>, <span class="script">template.XULAttr("wraparound")</span>, <span class="script">template.XULAttr("hidespinbuttons")</span>, and <span class="script">template.XULAttr("textbox.value")</span>.</li> <li><code>password</code>: A textbox that hides what is typed, used for entering passwords.</li> <li><code>search</code>: <span class="script">gecko_minversion_inline("1.9.1")</span> A textbox intended for searching. The command event will fire as the user modifies the value. A listener for the command event should update search results. If the <span class="script">template.XULAttr("searchbutton")</span> attribute is set to <code>true</code>, the command event is only fired if the user presses the search button or presses the <code>Enter </code>key. You may specify grey text to appear when the search box is empty using the <span class="script">template.XULAttr("emptytext")</span> attribute, and a timeout may be set for the command event using the <span class="script">template.XULAttr("timeout")</span> attribute (defaults to 500).</li> <li><code>timed</code>: <span class="script">template.deprecated_inline()</span> This textbox will fire a command event after the user types characters and a certain time has passed. The delay is set with the <span class="script">template.XULAttr("timeout")</span> attribute. The command event will fire if the user presses the <code>Enter </code>key. The <code>timed</code> type is deprecated in Gecko 1.9.1 and the <code>search</code> textbox may be used instead.</li>
</ul>
<div class="noinclude">
<h3 name="See_also">See also</h3>
<ul> <li><span class="script">template.XULAttr("type")</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="noinclude">
<p><span class="script"> wiki.languages( { "ja": "ja/XUL/Attribute/textbox.type", "pl": "pl/XUL/Atrybut/textbox.type" } ) </span></p>
</div></body></content>